



Herndon, VA 20170



507-213-4872



zakyah@proton.me

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Full Stack Web Development

Career Foundry, Berlin

Google IT Support

Google January 2021

Bachelor of Commerce

Accounting Osmania University, Hyderabad , India April 2010

WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

- https://github.com/meetZak
- https://meetzak.github.io/portfolio/
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/zakariaabdi-03414725b

LANGUAGES

English:

Full Professional

ZAKARIA ABDI

SUMMARY

User-minded Web Developer with a background in mental health. Able to translate skills in teaching and implementing evidence-based practices to effectively communicate with clients and create purposeful web solutions. Driven to grow expertise in website development by utilizing an analytical mindset and creativity to design responsive apps from start to finish.

SKILLS

- Front-End Skills: HTML, CSS
- Web and Application Servers
- · Javascript Libraries and Frameworks
- Azure Deployment
- Databases: Oracle, SQL Server, MongoDB
- · Data Modeling

EXPERIENCE

ASSISTANT MANAGER

Albryte Support Services | Sterling, VA | December 2020 - Current

- Assisted with building life and social skills useful for everyday activities and interactions.
- Planned and implemented individualized interventions as part of behavior treatment plans.
- Leveraged database management system to track and report service hours, details
 of activities and progress on goals.
- Reviewed information and elements regularly on websites and pages for accuracy and functionality.
- Assisted in developing and maintaining user-friendly websites.

OFFICE COORDINATOR

Home Instead Senior Care | Manassas, VA | November 2020 - February 2021

- Organized workloads to streamline tasks and efficiently oversee day-to-day operations under tight deadlines.
- Supported internal team members with technical knowledge, operational support and exemplary customer service.
- Input accurate account data to efficiently update company database and maintain detailed records.

RIDESHARE DRIVER

Uber And Lyft | Baltimore, MD | June 2019 - November 2020

· Achieved consistently high customer scores due to exceptional service.

French:

Full Professional

Arabic:

Professional

REFERENCES

Mohamed Idriss Tell: 443-310-0126

Email:mohamed6044@gmail.com

Ilyas Omar

Tel: 443-599-3072

Email: ilyasmusa212@gmail.com

• Cleaned vehicle regularly to maintain professional appearance.

PRODUCTION OPERATOR

HS Bakery | Baltimore, MD | March 2017 - May 2019

- Examined final products for conformance with quality and design standards.
- Recommended process improvements to enhance operational safety and efficiency.
- Troubleshot equipment problems to repair or report diagnostics.
- Documented daily production data and submitted accurate time logs to keep management up-to-date.

SALES ASSOCIATE

7 Eleven Store | Baltimore, MD | January 2016 - January 2017

- Assisted teammates with sales-processing tasks to meet daily sales goals.
- Built trusting relationships with customers by making personal connections.

SHIPPING AND RECEIVING ASSOCIATE

US Embassy Djibouti | Djibouti, Republic Of Djibouti | September 2012 - January 2015

- Produced daily reports on shipments, team performance and financial numbers.
- Checked customer orders, labeling and documentation prior to shipment to avoid delays.

CARGO SUPERVISOR

DHL Global Forwarding | Djibouti, Republic Of Djibouti | February 2011 - September 2012

- · Produced bills of lading and updated shipment status information.
- Adhered to airline cargo policies, monitored operations and reported discrepancies to management for review.